NAFIS HAIDER

Mobile: +91-9727719787, 9852533041 Email: nafis_haider26@rediffmail.com, nafishaider89@amail.com

Dear Sir/Madam,

It was with great interest that I read in the e-mail for the position of **DY. Manager/ Manager EHS** in your esteemed organization. In response, I enclose my updated resume for your consideration.

Review of my credentials will confirm that I am capable of serving as the catalyst for achieving revenue objectives and organic growth through effective contributions. I possess **8 Years & 11 months** of experience as an "EHS Professional" in Installation & Commissioning of equipments, Fabrication & erection of structures, in Cement Industry, Steel Industry, High Rise building construction, Water Management, T & D, GIS, Solar Power (PV & CSP), Refinery as well as in Process Plant (Auto-Mobile Industry).

I am currently associated with *Graziano Trasmissioni India Pvt. Ltd.* and *Posted in Sanand (Ahmedabad) Plant* as an "Assistant Manager- EHS". It is a Swiss MNC which deals in the manufacturing of Transaxles, Synchronizers, and Continuous Variable Transmission (CVT) etc. Our Valuable Clients are John Deere, Tesla, CNH (Case-New Holland), Ingersoll Rand (IR), L&T, JCB and Telcon etc.

I understand that working for your organization requires a candidate who is team oriented and is able to deal with people in various departments. I am confident that I possess these skills, which will help me to perform the job efficiently and effectively.

My goal is to transit my enthusiasm, creativity and experience into a position, where I continue to provide the strategic and tactical leadership critical to retaining valued customers of an organization. I am certain that my presence in your team will prove to be beneficial to your organization. As such, I would welcome an opportunity to speak with you to evaluate your needs and share my ideas.

Thanking you.

Sincerely,

NAFIS HAIDER

Enclosure: Resume

NAFIS HAIDER

Mobile- +91-9727719787, 9852533041 Address- C/o- Md. Sabir Ansari, E.S.I. Dispensary, Rd.No-4, Jawahar Nagar, Mango, Jamshedpur, Jharkhand, India

Email: nafis haider26@rediffmail.com

nafishaider89@gmail.com

=\

Seeking challenging position in the field of "Environment, Health & Safety" to utilize my experience & potential to the maximum for the benefits of the organization to achieve the set EHS Objectives/ Targets by the organization.

SNAPSHOT

A seasoned professional with **8 Years & 11 months** of rich & qualitative experience in the field of "Environment, Health & Safety (EHS)" in construction of various Industries like, Cement, Steel, GIS, T & D, Solar Power (PV & CSP), Water Management, High Rise Building, Refinery & currently associate in Process Plant (Auto-Mobile Industry).

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Working as an "Assistant Manager-EHS" from 18th Nov 2013 to till date in Graziano Trasmissioni India Pvt. Ltd., posted in Sanand (Ahmedabad) manufacturing unit.

- To develop occupational health, safety and environment systems, including policies, procedures and manuals.
- Promote occupational health and safety within the organization and develop safer and healthier workplace.
- Planning, scheduling and ensuring implementation of safety inspections, Safety Observation Tour(s) (SOT's) and audits (Internal & External) of the facility.
- To Identify and test work areas for potential accident and health hazards, such as toxic fumes and explosive gas-air mixtures, and implement appropriate control measures.
- Conducting Safety Committee & Sub Committee Meeting at regular interval.
- Conduct training sessions for management, supervisors and workers on health and safety practices and legislation.
- Promote "Safe Acts" and abstain from working under "unsafe working conditions" while
 Identifying engineering controls and ensure implementation of safety during commencement of
 production batches.
- Conducting safety campaign, safety motivational program and distributing prize among workers to motivate them regarding safety.
- Prepare MIS on EHS Performance of the project/plant & report periodically to different hierarchical level.
- Monitoring, maintain & assist in procurement of Fire Equipments e.g. Fire Extinguishers, Fire Hydrant system and suggest departments for appropriate PPEs according to the process.
- Handling & Monitoring of ETP & STP and all legal correspondence with GPCB, DISH and other like TSDF site, BMW Requirement & other regulatory monitoring agencies.
- To ensure the implementation of EMS 14001 & OHSAS 18001 system and its compliance.
- To maintain all statutory records on line and all document related to EHS matter.
- Conducting various mock drills (Fire, Work at Height, Emergency Preparedness, and Rescue Plan etc.) in plant.
- Keeping records of all injuries and investigate root cause & suggest remedial measures to avoid any future re-occurrence of the same.
- Conducting Third Party Inspection of various Lifting tools, Pressure vessels and other related machineries from the authorized competent person.

Worked as a "Regional Coordinator-EHS" from 9th Nov 2011 to 15th Nov 2013 in Schneider Electric Infrastructure Ltd. (Formerly Areva T&D India Ltd), posted in Noida and looking after the sites running in Delhi NCR, U.P, J&K, Punjab & Rajasthan regions.

- Preparing EHS Plan and Implementation of same.
- Attending Kick Off meeting with clients and fixing the safety Plan for new projects.
- Motivate the workers, conducting Safety Induction/Training & Motivation Program.
- To keep in readiness fire fighting squads, first aid help and P.P.Es.
- Inspection of Scaffolding as per the BS-5973 with tagging system.
- Documentation of all activities, Frequency/ Severity Rates, Accident/ Near Miss.
- Preparing the Monthly EHS Report of various sites running.
- Conducting the monthly EHS meeting with contractor and site Manager and discussing the issues related to safety and fixing it.
- Strictly following Permit system with the help of making Risk Assessment.

Worked as a "Safety Engineer" from 01st April 2011 to 31st Oct 2011 in Larsen & Toubro Ltd (L&T) at the site of Tata Steel Plant (TISCO) 3MT/Anum I-BF Expansion Project in Jamshedpur.

- To comply with the safety Advisory and Standards.
- To investigate regarding cause and the nature of accident & accident proneness.
- Hazard Identification & taking Control measure at construction sites.
- To implement work Permit System and ensure safe completion of work activity.
- To motivate the workers for safety by Tool Box Talk, Safety Induction and Training.
- To identify hazardous jobs, processes as well as hazardous zones in work place.
- Inspection of PPEs, Tools & Tackles, Winch, Welding-Cutting Set, & Electrical Equipment.
- To adopt corrective measures to contain hazards & reporting to site in-charge.
- Coordinating for emergency preparedness, rescues, Firefighting and first aid cases.
- To inculcate the spirit of safety by launching safety chat, safety meeting & awards.
- Conducting weekly safety meeting with project Manager and other HODs to overcome the safety issues at site.
- To implement Lock-Out and Tag-Out (LOTO) system.
- · Mock Drill on fire fighting and working at height.
- Preparing Lifting Plan for heavy Lifting activity.
- Conducting Safety campaign, Safety Skit to increase the awareness level of workmen.

Worked as a "Senior Safety Officer" from 24th April 2009 to 29th March 2011 in Lafarge India Pvt. Ltd at the site of Jojobera 1.2 MTPA Grinding Unit Expansion Project at Jamshedpur (Jharkhand).

- Safety Awareness / Training to employees/ Induction to new Entrants.
- Preparing Job Safety Analysis (JSA) and Risk Assessment.
- Electrical Safety inspection & Take control measure at construction sites.
- Inspection of PPEs, Tools-Tackles, Winch M/C, Welding M/C and Gas-Cutting Set.
- Making periodical safety inspection electrical equipment & tools- tackles checking.
- Accident / Incident / Near Miss Reporting & Investigation.
- Hazard Identification & Risk Assessments (HIRA).
- Conducting Safety campaign, Safety Skit to increase the awareness level of workmen.
- Permit to work system, Documentation of all Safety requirements.

Worked as a "Safety Officer" from 21st May 2007 to 23rd April 2009 in M/S. S.P.Enterprises At the site of JUSCO & Lafarge India Pvt. Ltd. in Jamshedpur (Jharkhand).

- Organizing and Ensuring tool box /Safety Talk meeting before starting daily
- Daily inspection of work sites for locating hazards and issuing report.
- Periodic Inspection of Approved PPE's. & enforce the proper use & care of PPE.
- Inspection of electrical & mechanical equipment to ensure their operational safe working.
- Maintaining safety records and documentation.
- · Mock Drill on fire fighting and working at height.

PROFESSIONAL CREDENTIALS

- > IRCA Approved EMS Lead Auditor from "Bureau Veritas Certification (I) Pvt. Ltd." in Aug- 15.
- Certified Internal Auditor of QMS (ISO- 9001) & OHSAS 18001 from DNV GL in Apr- 2015.
- > First-Aid Training from Indian Red Cross Society (Ahmedabad) in Aug- 2015
- NEBOSH IGC-3 in Sep 2011 with "Credit".
- > **IOSH** from VCES (Patna) in **June 2011**.
- > P.G.D.I.S.M. (UGC-DEC-AICTE approved) from "GJUST" with 1st Div. in 2013.
- > M.Sc. in Environmental Science from "The Global Open University" with 1st Div. in 2013.
- > Diploma in Industrial Safety from NILEM (National Institute of Labour Education & Management).
- > Training on Working At Height from AST (Australian Skill Training Agency).
- > Training on LOTO & Confined Space Entry from (Global EHS Head- Oerlikon) in Ahmedabad.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

- Pursuing Engineering from Institution of Engineers, India (IEI, AMIE).
- ▶ **BCA** from Sikkim Manipal University with Grade "A" in 2009. [74%]
- ➤ **I. Sc.** (PHY-CHE-MAT) from Bihar Intermediate Education Council with **2**nd div in 2005. [50.40%]
- ➤ **Matriculation** from Bihar School Examination Board with **1**st division in 2003. [65%]

MAJOR PROJECTS & ACHIEVEMENT

- Successful Completion of Phase-I of Oerlikon Graziano Manufacturing Unit, from Nov-13 to Dec-2014 with 0.5 Million LTI free Man hours, Sanand (Ahmedabad).
- Successful Completion of Erection, Testing and Commissioning of 66/11 KV Sub Station (Client-Moser Baer) in Dec-12 Without LTI, Mandal (Gujarat).
- Appreciation Letter from Client (Areva Solar India Pvt. Ltd.) on successful Completion of Electrical equipment's Erection, Testing and Commissioning of Reflector Mfg. Unit of 100MW CSP (Concentrated Solar Power) Project of Reliance Industries Ltd. in Oct-12 without LTI, in Pokaran (Rajasthan).
- Appreciation Letter from Client (Chemtrols Solar Power Ltd.) on successful Completion of Erection, Testing and Commissioning of 33/11 KV Sub Station in June-12 without LTI, Ahmednagar (Maharashtra).
- Successful Completion of Erection, Testing and Commissioning of 132/33 KV GIS (Tata Iron & Steel Co.) in Sep-11 Without LTI, Jamshedpur.
- <u>Certificate for achieving 5 Million LTI</u> free Man hours in Lafarge India Pvt. Ltd. Jojobera Grinding Unit Expansion Project, in Mar-2011, Jamshedpur.

SKILL & EXPERIENCE

- ▶ Well versed with OHSAS 18001-2007 Standard.
- ➤ Internal Auditor (QMS) ISO- 9001 & OHSAS 18001 for Current Employer.
- ➤ Team Leader "Oerlikon Operational Excellence" (OOE) Campaign which includes, 5S, KAIZEN, LEAN Manufacturing, Value Walk etc.

STRENGTH

- > Willing to learn International standards.
- > Hardworking and team leading capability.
- > Team Working with Inter personal relations

PERSONAL VITAE

Father's name : Md. Sabir Ansari
Date of Birth : 26/01/1989
Gender : Male

Marital Status : Unmarried
Nationality : Indian
Religion : Islam

Language Known : English, Hindi, Urdu & Bengali.

PASSPORT DETAIL

 Passport No.
 : J8911628

 Place of Issue
 : PATNA (INDIA)

 Issued On
 : 01/07/2011

 Valid Till
 : 30/06/2021

DECALARATION

I hereby declare that all the particulars mentioned above in the CV are true.

Place: - Ahmedabad. (Nafis Haider)